An Open  Source Planning, Scheduling  and Execution System  for People
with Disabilities Affecting Time Management Skills

A person  with time management  disabilities may not remember  to eat,
even if hungry,  may not remember to turn the  temperature up, even if
cold.   There is  probably a  considerable economic  loss  incurred by
these disabilities,  let alone myriad problems  for individuals having
them.   A  popular misconception  is  that  these  people simply  lack
discipline.

To solve  this problem, we  employ planning, scheduling  and execution
software to the real life  domain which these people require.  For the
sake of this project we  have identified the most critical domains.

The way  the system works is  as follows.  Because the  user cannot be
counted  on to  remember  to do  something  at a  particular time,  an
interrupt  must  be  serviced   to  them  containing  the  appropriate
scheduling information.  To maintain the  world state, and to impose a
minimal  interference with  the normal  operations of  the  person, we
choose to employ a  system based on bidirectional audio communication.
That is, the  user should employ a headset  containing earphones and a
voice recognition microphone.  For instance, a bluetooth headset would
work, and would also provide  the advantage of being a wireless system
with very  little distraction.  There are already  many computers such
as  laptop and  other portables  which have  the ability  to  run this
software.

The current system uses sphinx2  for recognition and festival for text
to  speech,  both  of  which  are conveniently  accessible  as  Debian
packages.   We  are  working   on  using  sphinx4  for  more  accurate
recognition results.

Another  interesting aspect  of this  problem is  that dialog  must be
planned as well.   For instance, the user may,  in certain conditions,
need to become detached from the system, in which case the system must
verify that  the user's tasks  are sufficiently simple that  they will
come back into contact with it  in order to not violate the conditions
of 

Look into electronic elves.

Advice - plan into Manuel Veloso



We will want to develop COA planning capabilities.