<system>
  <title>Verber</title>
  <short-description>
    Contingency planning, crisis management
  </short-description>
  <medium-description>

    Traditionally,  planning systems  are  all about  finding ways  to
    solve  the combinatoric problem  of satisfying  a few  goals.  Why
    these goals are selected is  not usually of any consequence.  What
    we really need  is a system that understands  what happens if, for
    instance, you  do not  pay your rent.   Another thing, is  that it
    make sure  that the daily  average of some required  thing exceeds
    what it  needs to be, hence  ensuring that you  don't fall behind.
    So,  our  system  is  for  instance  able to  reason  as  to  what
    consequences will happen if certain actions are taken or forsaken,
    and on the  basis of this, determine what  it thinks are important
    goals.

    Involve some kind  of automatic relational multidimensional queue.
    Ensure that it looks at everything (completeness).  A planner that
    looks  at  all  possible  actions,  and calculates  what  is  most
    effective for you to do.

  </medium-description>
  <long-description>

    <b>Overview:</b>

    <p>According  to the  U.S. Army  Survival Manual,  it is  necessary to
    develop a "pattern of survival".   People do this with various degrees
    of  success.  Software  that  addresses these  issues  has real  world
    applicability.</p>

    <!--
	During times of extreme pressure, even the most prepared and composed
	professionals might not always remember to do everything at the right
	time. A checklist can prove invaluable in assisting supervisors to keep
	tense situations under control.
    -->

    <p>Advances in open source  temporal planning technology make possible
    the  creation  of  many   useful  real  world  planning  domains.   We
    demonstrate  one such domain  which necessarily  utilizes many  of the
    features  present  in  PDDL2.2.   This  includes  numeric  quantities,
    durative actions, and derived predicates.</p>

    <p>By leveraging this planning software, and integrating this planning
    domain with  a dialog  and execution manager  agent using  open source
    speech  recognition  and  text  to  speech tools,  we  demonstrate  an
    effective open source tool for time management and planning.</p>

    <b>Example:</b>

    <p>Here is the modest  first (anonymized) plan generated by Verber
    for buying  groceries.  It was mainly  to serve two  needs, to get
    integration with other modules smoothly, and to help me get to the
    store.  It uses  actual bus data generated by  the BusRoute Verber
    module.   I am working  on developing  query planning  domains, to
    plan  the generation of  sub-domains from  modules as  needed. The
    intention is  to increase  the coverage of  the domain to  such an
    extent that virtually all tasks  in day to day life are completely
    scheduled.</p>

    <pre>
      Plan computed:
      Time: (ACTION) [action Duration; action Cost]
      19.2500: (RIDEBUS USER BUS-71D-51 CULMORE-AND-DERRY HELMSHIRE-AND-BROOKS) [D:0.0000; C:1.0000]
      19.2500: (BUYGROCERIES USER FORBES-AND-MURRAY) [D:1.0000; C:1.0000]
      20.2500: (RIDEBUS USER BUS-71D-52 HELMSHIRE-AND-BROOKS CULMORE-AND-DERRY) [D:0.0000; C:1.0000]
    </pre>

    <p>Here is an ancient plan.</p>

    <pre>
      Plan computed:
      Time: (ACTION) [action Duration; action Cost]
      0.0000: (MOVE ANDY CS-LOUNGE DOHERTY-LOCKER-161) [D:0.1500; C:2.0000]
      0.1500: (PICK-UP ANDY LAUNDRY DOHERTY-LOCKER-161) [D:0.1000; C:1.0000]
      0.2500: (MOVE ANDY DOHERTY-LOCKER-161 FORBES-AND-CHESTERFIELD) [D:0.1500; C:2.0000]
      0.4000: (SET-DOWN ANDY LAUNDRY FORBES-AND-CHESTERFIELD) [D:0.1000; C:1.0000]
      0.5000: (WASH-LAUNDRY ANDY LAUNDRY FORBES-AVE-LAUNDROMAT FORBES-AND-CHESTERFIELD) [D:2.0000; C:1.0000]
      2.5000: (MOVE ANDY FORBES-AND-CHESTERFIELD BAKER-LOCKER-18) [D:0.1500; C:2.0000]
      2.6500: (PICK-UP ANDY ELECTRIC-RAZOR BAKER-LOCKER-18) [D:0.1000; C:1.0000]
      2.7500: (PICK-UP ANDY TOWEL BAKER-LOCKER-18) [D:0.1000; C:1.0000]
      7.0000: (MOVE ANDY BAKER-LOCKER-18 UC-GYM) [D:0.1500; C:2.0000]
      7.1500: (SHOWER ANDY TOWEL UC-MENS-LOCKER-ROOM-SHOWER UC-GYM) [D:1.0000; C:1.0000]
      8.1500: (MOVE ANDY UC-GYM BAKER-LOCKER-18) [D:0.1500; C:2.0000]
      8.3000: (MOVE ANDY BAKER-LOCKER-18 DOHERTY-4201) [D:0.1500; C:2.0000]
      8.4500: (SET-DOWN ANDY ELECTRIC-RAZOR DOHERTY-4201) [D:0.1000; C:1.0000]
      8.5500: (CHARGE ELECTRIC-RAZOR OUTLET0 ANDY DOHERTY-4201) [D:12.0000; C:1.0000]
      20.5500: (PICK-UP ANDY ELECTRIC-RAZOR DOHERTY-4201) [D:0.1000; C:1.0000]
      20.6500: (MOVE ANDY DOHERTY-4201 FLAGSTAFF-HILL) [D:0.1500; C:2.0000]
      24.0000: (SHAVE ELECTRIC-RAZOR ANDY FLAGSTAFF-HILL) [D:0.2500; C:1.0000]
    </pre>

    <p>This software aims to improve our ability to reason with the objective
    consequeunces of our actions, which is of course necessary in order to
    act morally and ethically.</p>

    <p>So  the possiblity  of incorporating  plans which  are very  robust is
    something we should certainly do  here since this improves the results
    and utility  of any planning  process, and is  in a certain  sense the
    entire reason we wish to do this.</p>

    <p>The system is named after the late Senior Chess Master Richard Verber,
    in the spirit illustrated by this quote:</p>

    <p><em>"After losing  a game to  the master, Jermaine Bush  realized that
    Verber had controlled  the outcome from the opening  move.  This was a
    mastery that  the boy yearned for -  both in his chess  playing and in
    his life. Yeah, he thought, control!"</em></p>

    <p>Verber already incorporates many important features.  It has
    support for plan cycles, launching code as a result of a planning
    action, domain microtheories, visualization, and an interactive
    execution monitor/dialog system.  It is easy to incorporate other
    systems and considerations into verber, simply by specifying a
    verber module consisting of a pddl file and programmable actions.
    Ultimately, HTNs will be exported from PSE to Manager/Verber and
    almost all activities will be guided using this combination, with
    monitoring sending results to RSR to measure goal
    accomplishment.</p>
  </long-description>
</system>